In addition to checking validity,
除了有效性之外
you'll want to check for sources of bias in your experimental designs.
还需要检查实验设计是否存在偏差
For humans, biases are often seen as bad but
对于人类来说 偏差经常都不是好事
adaptively can sometimes help you make quick efficient decisions.
但有时候能帮助我们快速做出决策
For an experiment, biases is always bad.
对于实验来说 偏差总是坏事
Bias in an experiment refers to
实验偏差是指
systematic errors that affect the interpretability of your results.
影响到结果可解释性的系统性错误
Here, we'll cover a few of the major biases that can be present in an experiment.
我们将介绍实验中可能会出现的几种主要偏差
One type of bias is a sampling bias,
一种偏差是抽样偏差
where your sample is not representative of the population as a whole.
即样本不能代表整个群体
This pops up a lot in non-experiments.
非实验性研究经常会出现这种偏差
People working in survey research often have to contend with biases in self-selection,
问卷调查人员经常需要处理自我选择性偏差
where respondents very frequently fail to respond to survey requests.
调查对象经常不会回复调查问卷
It's possible that those people who responded are
有可能回复的调查对象
qualitatively different from those who didn't.
与没有回复的对象之间有显著的区别
Maybe they have more time to take surveys
也许他们有更多的时间参与调查
or maybe it's because they're more invested in the survey topic.
也许他们投入到调查话题的精力更多
Careful matching of the collected data to the population
为了避免这种偏差造成的影响
is needed to overcome this kind of bias effect.
我们需要谨慎地将收集的数据与人群对应起来
But sampling bias isn't limited to non-experiments.
但是并非只有非实验性研究才会出现抽样偏差
We can also have this in an experiment if we're not careful.
如果操作不仔细的话 实验中也会出现这种偏差
Let's say that we're running the experiment on the quick view overlay,
假设我们要对快览叠加页面进行实验
but we have a problem with the random assignment.
但是随机分配有问题
What if customers are systematically assigned
从午夜到中午的用户
the control group between midnight and noon,
都系统性地分配到了对照组
and the experiment group between noon and midnight.
从中午到午夜的用户都分配到了实验组
The kinds of people who access the site during
在这两个时间段内
these time frames might not be equivalent to one another,
访问网站的用户人群可能不对等
introducing a bias into the analysis of the results.
导致结果分析存在偏差
Another type of bias is a novelty bias.
另一种偏差是新奇性偏差
As you might guess, this is a bias that comes
你可能已经猜到了
from the introduction of something new to customers.
这种偏差是因为向客户提供某种新功能导致的
For the quick view overlay example,
在快览叠加页面示例中
you might see an initial up or down tick in
由于叠加页面是全新的功能
usage due to the sheer fact that the overlay is something new.
可能会导致一开始的用户使用量上升或下降
Maybe users aren't used to the overlay at the start
或许一开始用户不习惯于叠加页面
causing them to temporarily hold off on making purchases.
导致他们暂时不会购买商品
After some time however,
但是 过了一段时间后
the novelty will wear off and users will get used to the changes.
叠加页面不再是新奇事物 用户将习惯于这种变化
This will let you see the true effect of the experimental manipulation.
这时候就能看到实验性操控的真正效果
For within subjects experiments,
对于组内实验
there are a few related biases based on the order of conditions.
我们需要注意与条件顺序相关的几种偏差
Primacy bias is somewhat related to novelty and
首要性偏差与新奇性偏差有关
refers to changes due to a condition being first in the order.
是指由于首先出现的条件导致的变化
On the opposite side,
相反
recency bias refers to changes due to conditions being last in the order.
新近性偏差是指由于最后出现的条件导致的变化
For example, if you present a number of
例如 假设向测试人员提供多种产品样本
product samples to testers and asked them to rate each of them,
并请他们对每个样本打分
testers might anchor their ratings around the value of the first one, a primacy bias.
测试人员可能会根据第一个样本的分数打分 这属于首要性偏差
Alternatively, testers might favor the last sample due
或者 测试人员可能会倾向于最后一个样本
to it being fresh in their minds, a recency bias.
因为最后一个记得最清楚 这属于新近性偏差
The presence of these primacy and recency effects is why it is
因为首要性偏差和新近性偏差可能会有影响
so important to make sure that the order of conditions is balanced.
所以一定要使条件的顺序达到平衡